<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>My Awesome Blog: Posts tagged 'Allston condo'</title>
  <description>My Awesome Blog: Posts tagged 'Allston condo'</description>
  <link>http://www.example.com/tags/Allston-condo.html</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 05:38:29 UTC</lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 05:38:29 UTC</pubDate>
  <ttl>1800</ttl>
  <item>
   <title>The Overseas Potential Tenant Scam</title>
   <link>http://www.example.com/blog/2014/03/30/the-overseas-potential-tenant-scam/?utm_source=Allston-condo&amp;utm_medium=RSS</link>
   <guid>urn:http-www-example-com:-blog-2014-03-30-the-overseas-potential-tenant-scam</guid>
   <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 05:38:29 UTC</pubDate>
   <description>
&lt;html&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.example.com/img/1x1.gif?utm_source=Allston-condo&amp;amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;amp;utm_campaign=%2Fblog%2F2014%2F03%2F30%2Fthe-overseas-potential-tenant-scam%2F" height="1" width="1" /&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We are trying to rent our Allston condo and received this inquiry from a scammer. I&amp;rsquo;m usually hyper-aware of online scams but I have to admit I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect it in this context. Though some things seemed off, I initially believed that it was genuine, partially because it was in response to our posting on Jen&amp;rsquo;s hospital mailing list. Only after consulting with our friends Greg and Alena did we figure it out (a huge thanks to them!).&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the initial inquiry email:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From: rebeccapepwilliamson@gmail.com [mailto:rebeccapepwilliamson@gmail.com] On Behalf Of Rebecca Williamson Sent: Tuesday, March 25, 2014 8:11 AM Subject: Interested In Securing Your Place You Have For Rent&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hi there,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How are you doing and hope every thing is fine&amp;hellip;I saw your rental listing and I will be moving in once I confirm availability and everything is settled between and Will a month rent plus security deposit be enough for you to hold the place before my arrival? When will the unit be available? I would not mind furnishing the place myself if the place is not furnished..I will be coming for a research program in the state on Anthropology &amp;hellip;A little more about me, Friendly, outgoing, considerate, easygoing, very clean, and responsible. Don&lt;code&gt;t smoke/do drugs. Don&lt;/code&gt;t have pets. Looking for: clean place to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please email me&amp;hellip; rebeccawilliamson0@gmail.com for any further questions needed for me to secure the place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;God bless Rebbecca&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The grammar is atrocious but maybe she was just typing fast. But I was excited to get an enthusiastic potential tenant and so believed it was real.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Jen replied with some additional details and then received a second email:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From: Rebecca Williamson [mailto:rebeccawilliamson0@gmail.com] Sent: Tuesday, March 25, 2014 11:56 AM Subject: Re: Interested In Securing Your Place You Have For Rent&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Thanks for the mail, and more so i appreciate your gesture.i will be coming any time the place is available and will like to secure the room before coming over, so plz kindly get back to me with the Final asking price,pics and If there is any application you can send it to me so that i can print it out and have it fill then bring it along when am coming over to the state,am from England,22yrs old.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Also i will like you to get back to me with your full Name,phone numbers and the postal address, cos i can get it forward to my dad cos he is responsible for the payment and please let me know the actual amount needed to secure the place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hope to read from you on the information needed asap for the payment to be issue out to you. Thanks Rebecca,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Some bigger red flags this time:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This person wants to rent the place without seeing it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You claim to be a (grad?) student from England, yet you cannot speak English?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Being more suspicious, I asked Greg and Alena if they ever had foreign tenants (who want to rent a place sight unseen). Greg replied that they get similar emails all the time and that he ignores them because it must be a scam.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Some quick Googling pretty much confirms that it&amp;rsquo;s a scam. I found &lt;a href="http://www.burnaby-apartments.com/scam-overseas-tenant.php"&gt;this site describing the scam&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scam: The Overseas Tenant An overseas individual (usually from Africa or the UK) contacts you via email saying they are moving to your area in the next few weeks due to a job transfer and needs a place to rent. Their email is full of rambling detailed personal information, assurances of their trustworthiness and honesty, usually overtly friendly and religious in nature. Even though they are highly educated professional individuals (engineers, doctors, scientists or ministers), their use of the English language, grammar and spelling is terrible. You are asked to please email the rental terms as well as the property details and pictures (even though it&amp;rsquo;s on your Ad listing) to them ASAP. Generally, these individuals want to rent your property sight-unseen, ask you to take your Ad offline (offering to pay you to do so) and sometimes even ask you to oversee the arrival of their furnishings. A third party will be issuing you a check on their behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Soon an authentic-looking check complete with watermarks arrives in the mail. These fake checks look so real that they even fool the bank tellers. However, the amount on the check is for way more than you agreed upon (sometimes they pre-warn you it&amp;rsquo;s going to be more) explaining the extra funds are to cover travel or moving expenses. Usually it creates a financial shortage for the tenant. They engage you emotionally, imploring you to deposit the check quickly (assuring you that the funds are indeed there) and ask you to immediately wire-transfer the difference to a foreign account, of course, inviting you to keep a generous amount for your trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The money is transferred as asked. The &amp;ldquo;tenant&amp;rdquo; never shows but has your money. The check that was sent to you bounces and you are left to cover the insufficient funds and overdraft fees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>